Hardeep Kaushal

NW Calgary, AB T3L 2Z1

+1 587-585-2494; k.hardeep@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/hardeepkaushal; Portfolio-KAUSHAL.pdf

Detail oriented and creative Graphic/Web Designer with a 10+ years of experience in designing graphics for print/web/multimedia and 5 years of experience in developing websites. I seek to deliver immersive, intuitive design solutions providing positive user experience thus increasing viewership by 90%. 15+ years' experience in customer service, demonstrate courtesy, empathy, and professionalism in gathering information from clients to establish the precise nature of their enquiry.

COMPETENCIES -----

Print, Web and Multimedia

- Logo design, corporate identity design, pictogram, press advertisement, press insert, flyer, brochure, poster, wrap advertisement, signage, book design, POS display: kakemono, exhibition stand, newsletter and emailing
- Design, develop and gamify a website
- Develop interactive ideas and concepts for video game and mobile application and Transmedia projects
- Create 3D models of products, textures, mapping and animations
- Video editing and motion designing

Software, Language and Other Skills

- Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Dreamweaver, WordPress, AfterEffects, Enovia 3DExperience, 3Dvia Studio Pro, Sound Forge, Axure, Camtasia, Word, PowerPoint and Excel
- HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Bootstrap
- Drawing, sketching, painting and photography
- Good interpersonal, listening, communication and organizing skills.
- Excellent writing and verbal communication skills in English, French, Hindi and Punjabi
- Excellent problem solving, analytical, logical thinking skills with positive attitude
- Ability to work as a team member or individually with the willingness to learn new skills

GRAPHIC / WEB DESIGNER WORK EXPERIENCE -----

Graphic Designer March 2021 – Dec 2021

Defend (helpusdefend.com) - Canada

• Brainstorming with the multidisciplinary team bringing out ideas to create a healthy and abuse free social media app "65 Square" and propose UX/UI design solutions

Graphic and Web designer

Oct 2015 – July 2017

Self-Employed - Ile-de-France, France

 Designed, developed and updated WordPress websites for CreaKala and SCIBDP France and created visual identity for different clients

Assistant 3D Creator Oct 2014 – July 2015

Kalista Solutions (now Visiativ Retail) - Pantin, France

 Updated Kalista Solutions' responsive website on WordPress and created 3D models and their textures for Armand Thiery, Bayer, Mattel, Reckitt Benckiser. Made real-time virtual visits using Dassault Systemes' software for Visiativ B2B Merchandising Software helping retail industry to define the best merchandising strategy to offer a fluid and smooth customer journey to trigger purchasing

Designer May 2013 – Sept 2013

Atos - Bezons, France

 Designed logo for different entities within Atos. Helped in increasing the growth of Atos business by designing and gamifying the SI STUDIO's intranet site to educate its professionals the importance of UX/UI design principles while developing the software solutions for their clients

Graphic and Web designer

July 2008 - Oct 2012

Campus Formations et Métiers (CFM) - Bobigny, France

• Conceived and developed the CFM and Elan Consulting websites on Dreamweaver achieving 90% increase in the student enrolment. In charge of print communication for the school and thus enhancing the school presence

OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE _____

Nov 2022 - June 2023

Taxpayer Service Agent CRA – Calgary, Canada

- Gathered information from taxpayers to establish the precise nature of their enquiry in a call center environment
- Researched possible responses or solutions using a variety of internal and external information sources and informed or educated taxpayers by providing information and explanations to taxpayers over the telephone in response to their personal tax enquiries
- Promote available CRA administered programs and resources like OTCHB Program

FC Associate 1 April 2021 – present

Amazon - Calgary, Canada

- Located and extracted merchandise from shelves and storage areas and confirmed merchandise information matches that of the work order and packaged orders for shipment orders as well as marked and labeled product containers
- Received and stowed inventory and inspected the merchandise for damage, flaws, and irregularities.

Bakery Decorator July 2020 – Nov 2020

Co-op Shawnessy – Calgary, Canada

- Opened the bakery section in the morning and stocked products in the showcase
- Prepared pastries for the showcase and organized the showcase display
- Assembled, designed and decorated cakes according to customer specifications
- Took cake orders from the customers and assisted them to select a specific design or cake as per their needs
- Sold bakery products to customers and packed the purchased items as per the store protocol

VOLUNTEER WORK ------

Cook (July 2015 - Nov 2016) : Sivananda Yoga Centre - Paris, Orléans and London (France and England)

Prepared vegetarian meals for 6 to 30 people

Gardener (June 2023 - present): Botanical Gardens of Silver Springs - Calgary, Canada

Carried out varied range of gardening duties

Government College of Arts - Chandigarh, India

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATION	
Amazon Software Development Training	2023
Diploma of Vocational Studies in Professional Pastry Making (DEP Pâtisserie) École Hôtelière de la Capitale – Quebec City, Canada	2019 - 2020
Specialized Masters in Interactive Digital Experiences Gobelins, Enjmin and CNAM – Paris, France	2012 - 2013
European Bachelor of Arts in Communication ICOGES – Paris, France	2004 - 2006
Bachelor of Fine Arts	1998 - 2002